# David Dietrich

Software Developer Waterloo, Ontario March 2023 david.drich@gmail.com github.com/godares79

## **Objective**

Self-directed learner seeking a Senior Software Developer position in a fast-paced and challenging environment. Thrives in ambiguity. Proven tech lead. 10+ years of experience. Strong collaboration skills and several years of experience mentoring junior developers.

## Work Experience

Google Software Engineer - Google Cloud USA/Japan/Canada Jan 2022 - Apr 2023

- Designed and built Terraform and Kubernetes configurations, release pipeline, and probers for single-tenant GKE clusters.
- Drove decision to migrate Cloud source-control product from GCP VMs to GKE, reducing the work required for the eventual public release by 3+ eng months.

 $Software\ Engineer$  -  $Android\ Platform$ 

Mar 2020 - Jan 2022

- Created new configuration system and migrated existing test definitions, resulting in an over 10x reduction in test definition LOC.
- Designed and built performance testing suite for Android platform modules, catching performance regressions much earlier in the development lifecycle.

Software Engineer, Tools and Infrastructure - Android Google Maps

Jan 2014 - Mar 2020

- Lead team tasked with improving developer velocity. We significantly improved test flakiness and test performance, reducing wall time of code submissions from 45 minutes to under 20 minutes.
   Resulting in 6+ eng-months of waiting time saved per year.
- Refactored build configurations for Android Google Maps to improve readability and build performance, reducing average wall time of incremental builds by approximately 5 minutes.
- Designed and built conformance test infrastructure and tests for Android Auto. This suite is shipped to OEMs for verification of their Android Auto implementation in vehicles.

## University of Waterloo

Waterloo, ON

Research Assistant: Formal Methods Lab

Sept 2011 - May 2013

- Created and extended modelling languages and model verification tooling in an automotive context.
- Performed research presentations for industrial partners and visiting researchers.

#### University of Alberta

Edmonton, AB

Web Developer

May 2011 - Sept 2011

Created web-based info system for storing, editing, and searching faculty profiles at the University
of Alberta using PHP, HTML, and JS.

#### Energy Navigator Inc.

Calgary, AB

Junior Software Developer

May 2009 - Aug 2010

- Code and tooling for AFE Navigator, an expenditure tracking platform for energy companies.
- Primarily worked in C#. Additionally, some VB.NET, Java, and PL/SQL.

## **Education**

## University of Waterloo

 $M.Math\ Computer\ Science$ 

Waterloo, ON 2011 - 2013

 Thesis Topic: A Mode-Based Behaviour Pattern for Feature Requirements, and a Generic Feature Interface

- GPA: **89/100** 

- List out publications if they fit...

## University of Alberta

B.Sc. Computer Science

- GPA: **3.6/4.0** 

Edmonton, AB 2006 - 2011

#### **Technical Skills**

Frameworks: Bazel, Kubernetes, GCP, Terraform, Git, Jenkins, Cloud Build, Protobuf, Puppet

Languages: Python, Java, GCL, Go

References available upon request